Preliminary Guide to the Word Works, Inc. records, 1971-2013 MS2047
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Word Works, Inc. records
1971-2013
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Word Works, Inc.
MS2047
9.75 Linear Feet
Collection contains by-laws, articles of incorporation, correspondence, personnel records, financial records, programs, the Word Works Washington Prize, publications, photographs, and audiocassettes. The material dates from 1971-2013. Copies of manuscripts submitted by the young, aspiring poets who contributed to The Word Works are included in this collection.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Historical or Biographical Note
Since 1974, Word Works has been the center of literary life in the Washington, D. C. metropolitan area. Because of its location, in the nation's capital, and the uniqueness of its mission, Word Works attracts the attention of poets nationwide and internationally. Word Works is a non-profit organization, originally funded exclusively by yearly grants from the National Endowment for the Arts. The small amount of federal funding was supplemented by private donations and proceeds from book sales, much of which went toward the cost of materials for future publications. Its staff consists entirely of volunteers. In 1990, the records of Word Works were given to the Department of Special Collections at the Gelman Library, George Washington University, Washington, D. C., with an additional donation in 2002. The records of The Word Works, Incorporated document the activities of a small poets' collective in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area. Word Works was established in order to provide opportunities for young, little-known poets to gain recognition for their talents. Recognizing that the success of a poet's career often depends upon obtaining that "first" publication or chance at public exposure, Word Works sponsors public readings of local poets at various locations in the Washington, DC area, especially the Joaquin Miller Cabin in Rock Creek Park every summer. Word Works also sponsors yearly poetry writing contests and publishes several books of poetry put together by local Washington, D. C. poets.
For more information on Word Works' current activities, see http://www.wordworksdc.com.
Collection Scope and Content
This collections contains by-laws, articles of incorporation, correspondence, personnel records, financial records, programs, the Word Works Washington Prize, publications, photographs, and audiocassettes. The material dates from 1971-2013. Copies of manuscripts submitted by the young, aspiring poets who contributed to The Word Works are included in this collection. The collection also includes copies of unpublished manuscripts (along with reviewers' notes) for several Word Works publications. Additionally, the Word Works Collection contains correspondence between the poet and the Word Works editors and information on many of the programs conducted by Word Works such as the Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series. The student of printing and publishing will be able to see how a book is written for publication, from raw manuscript to the finished form.
The records of Word Works were given to the Department of Special Collections at the Gelman Library, George Washington University, Washington, D. C., in 1990, with an additional accretion in 2002.
This collection is part of the Washington Writers Archives at Gelman Special Collections, which includes original manuscripts and records from writers's organizations in the Washington D.C. area.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: Administrative files, Activities files, Publications, Photographs, cassettes, and artifacts, and Oversized materials.
Books
Eleven books have been seperated from acc#2010.035 and added to the Special Collections stacks.These books have the phrase "Gift of Word Works Inc." within their catalog record.
Budget; Finance; Biography; Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Audiotapes
- Administrative files, 1971-1990; MS2047 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series, contains correspondence, meeting minutes and agendas, by-laws, articles of incorporation, personnel records, press releases, publications, and financial records. This material dates from 1971-90. These documents relate to the history of Word Works and specifically history about Joaquin Miller and The Joaquin Miller Cabin. The biographies are for the staff who ran Word Works, including its Board of Directors. The meeting agendas and minutes are for the Board of Directors. The financial records include documents that detail the grants received by Word Works, and various tax and budget forms.
  - Advertising, 1977-2007; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Advertisements and Brochures, 1986-2008; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Artists, undated; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Certificates of Amendment to Articles of Incorporation, 1976-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronologies, 1971-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Joaquin Miller and Miller Cabin Biographical/Historical Information, n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Organizational Information, n.d., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Statement of Change of Registered Office, Registered Agent, or Both, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, Alenier, Karren, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Personnel, Baldwin, Deidra, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personnel, Beall, James, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personnel, Editorial Board, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, Gerritsen, Yolanda, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Personnel, Joaquin Miller Cabin Coordinator, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Personnel, Kreiger, Frederic J., n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Personnel, Miscellaneous, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Personnel, Student Intern, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Publicity, 1993-2004; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous, Logos, n.d, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous, National Park Service Permit, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, Releases, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous, Requests for Volunteers and Donated Services, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, Map of Rock Creek Park, n.d, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Publications, Book Distribution, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Publications, Book Inventory, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Publications, The Bookstall, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publications, Certificate of Registration of a Claim to Copyright, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Publications, Kozmik Press Centre, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Publications, National Writers Union, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Publications, Publishing Agreements, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Publications, Sales Staff, College Division, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Publications, Vendor Profiles Questionnaire, n.d., undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Financial, Bank Statement, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Financial, Budget, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Financial, Contributions, 1987-2003; Series 1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Financial, Corporate Account, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Financial, Grants, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Financial, Grants, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Financial, Grants, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Financial, Grants, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Financial, Grants, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Financial, Income, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Financial, Invoices, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Financial, Publication Consignments, 1975-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Financial, Receipts, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Financial, Sales Inventory, n.d, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Financial, Tax Exempt Status Application, 1975-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Financial, Tax Exempt Status Filing Report, 1976-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Financial, Tax Withholding, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Financial, Miscellaneous, n.d., undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area, 1985-1991 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area, 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area, 1987-1991 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area - By Laws, 1985-1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Poetry Committee of the Greater Washington D.C. area, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1995; Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1983-2005 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1984-2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1994 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1989-2003 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1998 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Publishing agreements, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Washington D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities report forms, 1988-1990 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Activities files, 1978-2013; MS2047 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains programs and announcement flyers for events, poems, lists of poets scheduled to read at events such as the Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series and Poet's Jam Events, correspondence, and award recipients and the submitted poems entered in the Washington Prize and the Writers' Center Events. The material dates from1978-90.
  - Programs, 25 Year Celebration Workshops, 1999-2002; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1998 Arts and Writers' Retreat Brochures, undated; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Programs, Benefit Ball to Support the Arts, 1980 June 13 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Programs, Blending Artistic Boundaries, 1984 March 02 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Programs, A Celebration of New Books, 1986 December 14 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Programs, City Discovers 'Street Poetry', 1975 August 11 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Programs, Finding Creative Imagery, 1985 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Programs, Gypsy Women: Lauren Pomerantz, Elisavetta Ritchie, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Programs, In the Shadow of the Capitol, 1981 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Programs, Literary Masque, 1985 April 13 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Programs, New Poets Series, 1978 November 19 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Programs, Our Poets in Concert, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Programs, Performance Poetry Workshop, n.d., undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Programs, Planetarium Programs, 1984; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Programs, The Poet on Art, Thursday, Year(?)October 18 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Programs, Poetry Reading: E. Ethelbert Miller, Karren Alenier, Jim Beall, 1978 August 07 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Programs, Poetry Under the Stars, 1984 April 01 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Programs, Poetry Workshop: Center for Creative Non-Violence, 1989 May 09 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Programs, Proposed Workshops for DC's Ellington School of Arts, 1999-2005; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Programs, A Reading/Community Dialogue with Maureen Owen, Sunday, Year(?) July 26 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Programs, Streetside Poetry Reading, 1976 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Programs, Shaping an Artistic Consciousness, 1980 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Programs, The Word Works Banquet, 1980 February 08 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Programs, The Word Works Benefit at Singer's Studio, 1978 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Programs, Whose Woods These Are: Prepublication Readings, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Programs, Whose Woods These Are: Publication Party, Herb's Restaurant, 1983 October 17 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Programs, Young Author's Conference, 1983 November 29 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Programs, Younger Voices: Poetry from the Schools/Young Poets' Competition, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Programs, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin Poetry Series, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 April 14 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 June 09 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 July 12 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 July 26 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984 September 15 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 January 19 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 February 23 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 June 15 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 June 29 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 July 20 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 August 03 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1985 August 10 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Poet's Jam Events, 1984-1985; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - The Word Works Washington Prize n.d., undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Poetry Contest Entry Log, n.d., undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 February (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 February 04 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 August (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 September 18 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1979 October (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1983 July (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - The Writers Center Events, 1984 September 09 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Cafe Muse, 2002-2005; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cafe Muse guest log, 2002-2010; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 1988-1990; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin materials [1 of 2], 1982-1983; Series 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin materials [2 of 2], 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin guestbook, 1998-2006 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin poetry, 1999-2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin poetry, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Joaquin Miller Cabin poetry, 2004-2005 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Friends of the Library, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Arts retreat materials, 1996-1999 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Arts retreat materials, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Arts retreat: Tuscany, 2000-2001 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Washington Prize winners, 1995-1998 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Washington Prize winners, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - 25th Anniversary celebration materials, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Programs, 2000-2008 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Workshop evaluations, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - St. Marys College of Maryland workshop materials, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Promotional materials: fliers and catalogs, 2011-2013; Series 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Promotional materials, 1982-2017 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Promotional materials, 1981-2001 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Publications, 1974-2007; MS2047 Series 3; 2 Linear feet
  This series contains copies of publications and manuscripts of submissions to these publications, along with reviews of these publications. Also included in this series is much of the preliminary work to the anthology, "Whose Woods These Are." Lastly, a list of contributors biographies, publishers and books in print, along with the unpublished works can be found in this series.
  - Aspects of a Southern Story, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bad Names for Women, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Berta Broadfoot and Pepin the Short, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bliss, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Creature Comforts, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Emerging Detail, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - The End of the Hand, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Family and Other Strangers, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Hickey, the Days, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Inside Outside, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Love in Idleness, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Motherwriter, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Poet Upstairs, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Snake Country, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Stalking the Florida Panther, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Swan Research, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Wandering on the Outside, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - The Way Water Rubs Stone, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Way Water Rubs Stone, continued, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The Way Water Rubs Stone, continued, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - A Woman From Memphis, n.d., undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Poets comments, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Mockup, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Whose Woods These Are, "Foundations", n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Whose Woods These Are, "Mortar", n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Whose Woods These Are, "The Neighborhood", n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Whose Woods These Are, "Songs", n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Whose Woods These Are, "The Woods", n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Pre-Assigned Library of Congress Catalog Card Number, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Reviews, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Unbound Signatures - Blue, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Unbound Signatures - Tan, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Whose Woods These Are, Miscellaneous, n.d., undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Contributors' Biographies, A-F, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Contributors' Biographies, G-L, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Contributors' Biographies, M-R, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Contributors' Biographies, S-Z, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, Books in Print, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Publicity, Directory of American Poets and Fiction Writers, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Publicity, Directory of Poetry and Publishers, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Publicity, Dustbooks, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Publicity, Franklin Furnace Archives, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Publicity, International Publishers, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Publicity, Publication Notices, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished Submissions, Anonymous, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Unpublished Submissions, Comments, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Unpublished Submissions, A-F, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Unpublished Submissions, G-N, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Unpublished Submissions, O-Z, n.d., undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - The Bodies We Were Loaned [1/3], undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Bodies We Were Loaned [2/3], 2001 February 22 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - The Bodies We Were Loaned [3/3], undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [1/7], 2001 September 15 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [2/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [3/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [4/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [5/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [6/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Crow's Eye View: The Infamy of Lee Sang, Korean Poet [7/7], undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - One Hundred Children Waiting for a Train [1/4], undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - One Hundred Children Waiting for a Train [2/4], undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - One Hundred Children Waiting for a Train [3/4], undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - One Hundred Children Waiting for a Train [4/4], undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - By the Nest, 2008; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Urn Garden manuscript, undated; Series 3 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - James Howard Beal materials, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Periodical: The Montgomery Journal, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Newsletter: Coda, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Newsletter: Coda, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals: Poetry Flash, Carousel, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Periodical: Manager's Report, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - R.R. Bowker materials, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Love In-Idleness by Robert Zingarello, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Poems for Jacklyn, 1987-2006
  - Poems for Jacklyn, 1987-2006
  - Farewell to the Baby, Barbara Moore, 1990
  - Organizations, 1990-1991
  - Miles David Moore File, Correspondence, 1994-2006 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - The Cutoff, Jay Rogoff, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Toward Desire, Linda Lee Harper, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The Good Opinion of Squirrels, M.A. Schaffner, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Karren Alenier, Bumper Cars, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Spinoza's Mouse, George Young, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Good Opinion of Squirrels, Promotional Materials, 1996-1997 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Grant Application Witter Bynner Foundation for Poetry, 1997-1998 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - News from the Word Works, 2000-2007 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Poetry, Phoenix Suites, Undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Gilbert and Garbo in Love: A Romance in Poems, Undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Berta Broadfoot and Pepin the Short materials, Undated (Box 22, Folder 12)